(カカシ/オビト)間に合え！
- Please make it in time!
(２人)リン。
- Rin!
《カカシ : ありがとう リン。
Thank you, Rin.
Obito and I will be
joining you shortly.
俺もオビトも
そろそろ そっちへ行くよ。
また３人で ゆっくり話をしよう》
We can catch up then,
the three of us together.
Rin…
《オビト : リン 今度は あの世で→
This time, let's spend...
少し俺と
２人きりの時間を過ごそう》
some alone time together.
Just you and me.
《カカシは邪魔だ。
Kakashi would just be in the way.
ここに置いていくよ》
I'll leave him here.
YOU BETTER…
どうしてだ？
Why?
互いに覚悟はもう…。
I thought we had both resolved to…
お前の力は まだ今ここで必要だ。
Your power is still needed here!
(ゼツ)いったん チャクラを練り直しか。
We need to rebuild chakra again.
母さん 始球空間へ飛ぼう。
Mother, let's teleport to
the Root Time-Space…
You'll recover faster there, too.
あそこなら回復も早い。
なぜ 役にも立たない俺のために？
Why would you do this
for someone useless like me?
そんなことより
敵に注意しろ カカシ。
Never mind that.
Kakashi, be wary of the enemy.
《ナルト サスケ そして サクラか。
Naruto, Sasuke, and Sakura…
こいつらは今 大切なときだ。
This is a crucial time for them.
カカシ お前は
新しい世代の支えとして→
Kakashi, you must survive
and support the next generation.
まだ死ぬには早い》
It's too soon for you to die.
(ゼツ)そんなことをしてもムダだ ナルト。
It's totally useless, Naruto.
そいつはもうダメだ。
He's a goner.
ゴミのように朽ちて死ぬ。
He'll rot away like trash and die.
よせ ナルト やつの言うとおりだ。
Enough, Naruto.
He's right.
チャクラをムダに使うな。
Don't waste your chakra.
なぜ そんなやつに肩入れする？
Why do you sympathize with him?
そいつは もともと
お前らの敵だった男だろ。
He was originally your enemy, right?
まぁ かといって
こちらとしても裏切られた→
Then again,
he's a traitor to us now.
どっちつかずのクズだがな。
A loser on both sides.
敵味方双方から忌み嫌われ→
Hated and resented
by friend and foe alike,
with no one to call
comrade or family…
悲しんでくれる
仲間も肉親もいない。
そいつは独り 何も残らない。
He's alone, with nothing left.
大切な人を亡くし
夢を叶えることもできず→
He's lost everyone precious to him,
and he can't realize his dreams.
And after being used up,
he's helpless at the end…
利用されたあげく
最後にうろうろと→
失敗だらけのマヌケか。
He's a fool, filled with
nothing but mistakes…
You've done nothing but—!
(ナルト)てめえ さっきから…。
そうだな。
You're right…
((オビト : リン もう一度…。
Rin…again…
もう一度
キミのいる世界をつくろう。
I'll create a world where
we can be together again.
《俺が この世の因果を→
I shall…
sever the nexuses…
断ち切る》
of this world.
(マダラ)あ…。
さぁ 動け 俺が復活するまでの間。
Now go on…
Until I will be revived…
お前が…。
You shall be…
(長門)誰だ？
Who are you?
うちはマダラだ。
I am Madara Uchiha.
勝者だけの世界
平和だけの世界 愛だけの世界。
But a world of just
victors, peace, and love…
それらだけの世界を
つくることもできる。
Such a world can be created too.
If you allow us to collaborate,
you can learn how.
我々が協力すれば
そのやり方を知ることができる。
Let's go, Konan… Nagato.
(弥彦)行くぞ 小南 長門。
こいつらは信用できない。
We can't trust these guys!
二度と俺たちに近づくな。
Don't ever approach us again!
お前も いずれ
気づくことになる。
You'll eventually realize it too.
(ヤグラ)何やつだ！
Who are you?
You are going to be
very useful to me.
お前には せいぜい
役に立ってもらうとしよう。
RIN NOHARA
Summoning Jutsu!
口寄せの術！
《ミナト先生…》
Minato Sensei…
(我愛羅)あ～ あ…。
第四次忍界大戦
ここに 宣戦を布告する。
I hereby declare the start of
the Fourth Great Ninja War.
(カブト)どれも強者揃いだ。
They each have formidable strength.
And I have even more
up my sleeve.
それに 僕の持っている駒は
これだけじゃない。
いいだろう 手を組んでやる。
So be it.
We will join forces with you.
絶望を教えてやるのさ。 丁寧にな。
They will know despair thoroughly.
(みんな)うわ～！
うっ… うわっ。
(うわ～っ！))
お前の言うとおり→
You're right.
罪人の俺に ふさわしい最後だ。
It's an end worthy of
the criminal that I am.
《サスケ : 瞳力が戻った》
My Visual Prowess is back!
チッ。
(サクラ)ここは前に来た…。
We've been here before!
Did she change worlds again?!
また世界を変えたのか。
ナルト！
Naruto!
今度は俺が陽動をかける。
Naruto, I'll handle
the diversions this time.
He's beyond help.
そいつは もう助からん。
こっちへ来い。
Come with me.
先に行く。
I'm going on ahead!
くそっ くそっ… くそ～っ！
Damn it! Damn it!
Damn it!
もういい… ありがとうな ナルト。
That's enough.
Thank you, Naruto
(オビト)俺は お前と戦って→
After fighting you,
I feel like I've woken up.
何か目が覚めたような気がした。
((俺も お前も
しょせん 無力な忍だ。
You and I are both powerless shinobi.
お前も…。
You…
いや 誰でもいずれ→
no, I should say everyone…
俺のようになるのだからな。
will eventually end up like me.
俺は てめえみてえにはならねえ。
I'll never end up like you!
何度も言ってんだろ。
How many times
do I have to tell you?!
俺がなりてえのは火影だ！
My dream is to become
the Hokage!
こんな世界のために→
There is no reason to keep on
fighting for a world like this.
もう戦う意味はないはずだ。
この世界も数分で終わる。
In a few minutes,
this world will be gone anyway.
そうまでして なぜ戦う!?
Why do you still fight?!
まっすぐ 自分の言葉は曲げねえ。
Because it's my Ninja Way.
(それが 俺の忍道だからだ))
I never go back on my word.
((オビト : うおぉ～！
うわっ！
(リン)無理しないで
今日はここまでにしよう。
Don't overdo it.
Let's call it a day.
いや 俺は諦めねえ。
No, I'm not giving up.
約束したろ。
俺は火影になるんだからな。
Didn't I make a promise?
That I'm gonna become
the Hokage!
(もう…))
Really…
まるでな お前を見ていると→
It was as if I saw my past self
when I looked at you.
昔の自分を見ているようで
今の自分を後悔した。
And I regret what I am now.
だが 何よりそれが
なぜだか嬉しくもあってな。
But for some reason,
it also made me happy.
昔 ガキの頃は何度も
火影になった自分を想像してよ。
As a kid, I would imagine myself
as Hokage so often.
興奮と不安と
あの何とも言えぬ気持。
That indescribable feeling
of exhilaration and anxiety…
それを思い出させたからだろう。
I think you brought
that all back for me.
((２人 : はっ！
ウッ…。
泣くな オビト。
Don't cry, Obito.
You'll get laughed at.
そんなザマじゃ 笑われるぞ。
わかってる。
それに 忍の世界は争いだらけだ。
I know.
Besides, the world of shinobi
is all about fighting.
平和な世とは程遠い。
It's nowhere near
a peaceful world.
そんなもの
俺が必ず終わらせてやる。
And I'll put an end to it,
no matter what.
(アスマ)おい お前らだけじゃない。
Hey, you're not the only ones.
Don't forget that we're here too.
俺たちもいることを忘れるなよ。
ああ そうだな。
Yeah, that's right.
リン 俺は…。
Rin… I…
(オビト)それは？
(カカシ)上層部の決定だよ。
What's that?
The higher-ups have decided.
オビト お前が次の火影に決まった。
Obito, you're going to be
the next Hokage.
だが 実力なら お前だって…。
But you're just as qualified…
A supportive role suits me better.
俺は サポート役が性に合ってる。
リンだって きっとそう言うさ。
I'm sure Rin would say
the same thing.
But if you screw up,
I won't hesitate
まっ お前がヘマをしたら 容赦なく
次の火影に立候補するけどな。
to step up as a candidate
to become the next Hokage.
なんだと？
What?!
頑張れよ。
Do your best!
RIN NOHARA
This is driving me crazy!
気がめいるな。
来る日も来る日も書類 書類。
All this paperwork
day in and day out.
しかたないだろ。
お前は火影なんだから。
That can't be helped…
You're the Hokage now.
うへっ。
それに この程度の雑務→
Besides, something like this
sure beats having to fight every day.
戦いに追われる日々より
ずっとマシだ。
確かにな。
That's for sure.
ハハッ。
火影様！
It's the Hokage!
Lord Hokage! Hello!
お疲れさまです。
火影様 見回りですか？
まあな。
Lord Hokage,
are you on your rounds?
Well, yes.
Yeah, right!
とか言って ほんとは
サボってるだけじゃねえの？
You're just goofing off, right?
フン お前じゃあるまいし。
なんだと！
Speak for yourself!
What?!
やるのか？
やめなさい！
うぁ～っ！
Wanna make something of it?
Cut it out!
って なんで
俺だけなんだってばよ！
Why did you hit only me?
Because you were rude
to Lord Hokage!
(サクラ)だいたい
火影様に対して失礼でしょ。
Seriously…
まったく お前のおかげで
平和なもんだ。
It's so peaceful, thanks to you.
俺だけじゃない。
今日まで里を支えてきた→
Not just me.
It's everyone who did their best
to support the village.
みんなの力があってこそだ。
It would be nice to talk
to Rin someday.
(いつか リンに話せるといいな。
ああ))
Yeah.
(オビト)里があり 仲間がいて
火影の俺がいると…。
Imagining the village, friends,
and me as the Hokage…
いまさらな。
Even after all that's happened…
その想像するだけで 心の穴が
埋まっていく気がしたよ。
Just the thought of it seems to
fill up the hole in my heart.
フッ。
Maybe it's because it's the end,
最後だからか 俺は… 何をペラペラと。
I find myself rambling all of a sudden.
((イタッ！
Ouch!
(リン)強がって 傷を隠しても ダメ！
Don't act tough and
hide your wounds.
ちゃんと見てんだから。
I'm always watching you.
オビトは 火影になるって
私に約束した。
You promised me that
you would become Hokage, Obito.
いい？ 私だって
この戦争を止めたい。
Listen, I want to stop this war too.
世界を救いたいと
本気で思ってるよ。
I really want to save the world.
So I've decided to stick by
your side and watch over you.
だから オビトのこと そばで
しっかり見守るって決めたの。
(リン)あなたを救うことは
世界を救うのと同じなんでしょ？
You told me saving you
was the same as saving
the world, remember?
うん…。
Yeah!
私が見張ってるってことは→
Since I'm keeping
an eye on you,
もう なんにも
隠しごとはできないよ。
you can't hide anything
from me anymore.
うん！ うん！
Okay! Okay!
頑張れ オビト！
Go for it, Obito!
Become Hokage and show me
how you'll save the world.
火影になって かっこよく
世界を救うとこ 見せてね！
That's another promise!
それも 約束だよ。
(行こう))
Let's go!
(オビト)お前には これから まだ
多くの苦しみがあるだろう。
A lot more suffering
likely awaits you, Naruto.
But don't ever change
だが それでも
お前は変わることなく→
and hang on to your Ninja Way.
その忍道を貫き通せ。
You once told me that
いつか 俺に言ったな？
never going back on your word
is your Ninja Way, right?
まっすぐ 自分の言葉は曲げない。
それが俺の忍道だ…。
だったかな？
あぁ。
ナルト！
お前は 必ず 火影になれ。
あぁ！
フッ！
(ゼツ)裏切り者の虫ケラが
やっと死んだか。
虫ケラは 虫ケラでも
このしつこさは ゴキブリだったな。
ハハハハハ！
オビトを笑うな。
ナルト…。
ナルト… お前も
これ以上 刃向かってると→
崩れて灰になった 哀れでみじめな
そいつと同じになるんだ。
火影になろうとしたオビトは
俺には…。
なっ！
かっこよくしか見えねえよ！
((リン…。
待ってたよ。
(オビト)そうか。 待たせて すまねえ。
(リン)いろいろ
道に迷ったみたいだね。
あぁ… ここに来るまで
いろいろ あってよ。
リン…。
俺 リンとの約束…。
ううん。
オビトは頑張ったじゃない。
ずっと 見てたんだよ。
(行こう))